Andrew Paschall

602.615.0610 | paschallandrew@gmail.com | Phoenix, AZ

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andrew-paschall **Website:** andrewpaschall.com

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

I am a hands-on Salesforce Solutions Architect with 14 years of experience building business web applications. I specialize in technical Salesforce roles that require strong presentation and facilitation skills, obtaining stakeholder acceptance by understanding and delivering the right strategic vision, simplifying complex processes, and driving the difficult conversations necessary to execute business strategies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Salesforce, JavaScript, LWC, Apex, Node.js, APIs, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, SOQL, SQL, GitHub, Mulesoft, Agile

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce Development Manager | Allstate Identity Protection | Remote

Feb 2021 – Present

- Build, manage, and mentor a high-performing team of 5 Salesforce developers and admins
- Deliver live product demonstrations, technical Q&A, and roadmap presentations to Executive teams
- Serve as trusted advisor to all internal/external customers, lead requirements gathering sessions, manage expectations and negotiate solutions to complex problems with both customers and third-party partners
- Help customers define business needs, guide prioritized data creation efforts and data strategy to address critical business questions
- Continued hands-on development of key features while leading security, code, and design reviews with team
- Spearheaded redevelopment of legacy web application in use by 1,500+ clients, resulting in 20+ new features, reduction of 60% in save/load time and NPS score increase of 40+ points (Salesforce Community Cloud)

Salesforce Solutions Architect | <u>Allstate Identity Protection</u> | Remote

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- Technical lead on team implementing custom Sales, Service and Community Cloud solutions
- Developed all functional solution architecture and proof-of-concepts; gave 20+ live demos to key stakeholders
- Implemented a Salesforce-native Contract Lifecycle Management solution (Conga CLM) to house all contract data, templates, signing, process documentation, maintenance and SLAs on a single Salesforce cloud
- Designed and launched call center applications in Salesforce servicing over 2 million end users; included Service Cloud, LWC, Apex, JavaScript, SLDS, REST APIs, MuleSoft (middleware), and Genesys (telephony)
- Facilitated continuous interaction between users, development and QA teams throughout the SDLC, resulting in a 95%+ testing success rate
- Developed NetSuite ERP integration using LWC, Apex, and Mulesoft to sync payment data for 5,000+ clients

Salesforce Solutions Architect | Shellback Semiconductor | Phoenix, AZ

Mar 2018 – Mar 2019

- Led and completed company-wide implementation of Salesforce Lightning over 6 months. Tools included Custom Object Design, LWC, Visualforce, Flows, Process Builder, SOQL queries, Data Loader and Apex triggers
- Built rich, highly performant applications using Lightning, Apex, and LWC JavaScript frameworks
- Authored business requirements document for Salesforce re-implementation: led requirements gathering sessions, requirements analysis, solution assessment and validation, use cases and interface mock-ups
- Reduced quarterly forecast error by more than 45% via data analysis and custom Salesforce reporting

User Experience Director (UX) | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2013 – Dec 2017

- Responsible for the design, planning, configuration, programming, delivery and maintenance of the company's public website, mobile app, Salesforce CRM, and desk.com support portals
- Managed Salesforce integrations with Hubspot, Marketo and the company's proprietary technology platforms
- Salesforce developer and systems administrator for over 300 users
- Led all UX/UI design for the company's mobile/tablet application for iOS, Android and mobile web
- Automated Marketing processes via configuration and customization of Salesforce reports, dashboards, triggers and workflows

Lead Web Developer | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2011 – Apr 2013

- Overhauled the company website using modern HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript standards; generated 80% more leads via email capture forms, reduced bounce rate by 30%
- Implemented open-source mapping tools to replace the company's existing proprietary application, saving more than \$40,000 per year
- Designed interactive help system and training documentation; reduced customer support calls by 30%

Web Developer (Freelance Consulting) | Cleartorch, Inc. | Phoenix, AZ

Feb 2006 - Apr 2011

- Provided full-stack web development and marketing automation consulting to small to medium size companies; primarily servicing the Financial Services, Healthcare and Higher Education industries
- Defined business requirements, user stories and user personas
- Conducted UX research with real customers, presented findings and recommendations
- Created sketch, wireframe, prototype and visual mock-ups
- Advocated for web interaction design best practices with a focus on consistency and usability testing
- Conducted website performance testing and network configuration to optimize load times
- Worked with backend engineers and IT analysts to see projects through to completion
- Technology included HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress and Drupal

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Salesforce Platform Developer I Certified Salesforce Platform App Builder **B.A. English,** Arizona State University